<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Components on Documentation for the Scenic-Shop Calculators</title>
    <link>http://scenic-shop.com/calculators-formulae/components/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Components on Documentation for the Scenic-Shop Calculators</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language><atom:link href="http://scenic-shop.com/calculators-formulae/components/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ANSI Chain Calcs</title>
      <link>http://scenic-shop.com/calculators-formulae/components/chain_ansi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scenic-shop.com/calculators-formulae/components/chain_ansi/</guid>
      <description>Notes &amp;amp; Use A collection of lookups and calculations for ANSI standard roller chains.
All ANSI reference values are from manufacturers&#39; catalogues.
Calculations Length The chains&#39; length conversion between inches and pitches is calculated by the folling formula:
$$ L = P \times p $$
where:
$L$ = chain length, inches
$P$ = chain length, pitches
$p$ = chain pitch distance, determined from ANSI values
Weight The weight of the chain is calculated as&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plain Bearing PV</title>
      <link>http://scenic-shop.com/calculators-formulae/components/bearing_plainpv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scenic-shop.com/calculators-formulae/components/bearing_plainpv/</guid>
      <description>Notes &amp;amp; Use Calculates design values (velocity, force, and combined) of plain bearings when the following are true:
 For radial (journal) applications  the bearing rotates around a shaft, the rotational motion is continuous (as opposed to an ocillating), the load is applied perpidicular to the axis of rotation (radial).   For thrust applications:  the load rotates upon the bearing, around a fixed center point, the thrust bearing&amp;rsquo;s bearing surface is circular or annular, the rotational motion is continuous, the load is applied parallel to the axis of rotation, the load is uniform across the surface area of the bearing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bearing Rolling Life</title>
      <link>http://scenic-shop.com/calculators-formulae/components/bearing_rolling_life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scenic-shop.com/calculators-formulae/components/bearing_rolling_life/</guid>
      <description>Notes &amp;amp; Use Calculates design values related to lifetime for rolling element bearings when the following is true:
 The bearing operation is not characterized as an occilating motion; the spinning object tends to make full rotations at a roughly constant speed. The RPM shall be approximated as an average RPM over the lifetime of the bearing. The radial and thrust loads have been converted to an equivalent load as per the bearing manufacturer&amp;rsquo;s reccomendations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parallel Shaft Keys</title>
      <link>http://scenic-shop.com/calculators-formulae/components/keys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scenic-shop.com/calculators-formulae/components/keys/</guid>
      <description>Notes &amp;amp; Use Calculates for the selection and design of parallel keys in shafts. Only compressive and shear stresses are taken into account. This calculator does not take into consideration:
 tolerances related to proper fits in a keyway localized stresses strength of the shaft and/or hub relative to the key material abrasion and fatigue resistance stresses caused by key rolling or cyclic impact loads  All key depths are assumed to be (0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pulley Pressures</title>
      <link>http://scenic-shop.com/calculators-formulae/components/pulleys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://scenic-shop.com/calculators-formulae/components/pulleys/</guid>
      <description>Notes &amp;amp; Use Calculates:
 D:d ratios for given pulley and cable sizes Tread pressure  Pressure exerted on the groove by the load Wrap angle is taken into account, see image A round cable is assumed A properly-sized round groove is assumed, the nominal groove diameter is approximately:    $$ D_{groove} = 1.06 \times D_{cable} $$ - Note that the tread pressure as depicted in the figure below is not technically accurate, but more illustrative in nature.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
