<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Front Page? on Documentation for the Scenic-Shop Calculators</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/formulae/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Front Page? on Documentation for the Scenic-Shop Calculators</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/formulae/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ANSI Chain Calcs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/formulae/components/chain_ansi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/formulae/components/chain_ansi/</guid>
      <description>Notes &amp;amp; Use A collection of lookups and calculations for ANSI standard roller chains.
All ANSI reference values are from manufacturers&#39; catalogues.
Calculations Length The chains&#39; length conversion between inches and pitches is calculated by the folling formula:
$$ L = P \times p $$
where:
 L = chain length, inches P = chain length, pitches p = chain pitch distance, determined from ANSI values  Weight The weight of the chain is calculated as&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Helical Drum Cable Payout</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/formulae/drums/drums_helicalpayout/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/formulae/drums/drums_helicalpayout/</guid>
      <description>Notes &amp;amp; Use Calculates the payout (in feet), and total number of wraps for a grooved helical drum.
 The drum must be of constant pitch diameter This calculator will calculate for both bitter-end rigging and operating-loop rigging.  Figure Terms l = Groove lead, inches
Dpitch= Pitch diameter of drum, inches
w = Width of drum&amp;rsquo;s grooved surface, inches
nlines= number of lines:
 count each operating cable loop as 1 line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Max Unbraced Drum Length</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/formulae/drums/drums_unbraced_length/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/formulae/drums/drums_unbraced_length/</guid>
      <description>Notes &amp;amp; Use Calculates the maximum distance between internal braces in a helical cable drum.
 The drum must be of constant pitch diameter  Figure Terms ν = Poisson&amp;rsquo;s ratio for drum material
   Material Poisson&amp;rsquo;s ratio     Steel, mild 0.303   Steel, high carbon 0.295   Steel, Cold-rolled 0.287   Aluminum 0.334   Aluminum, 6061-T6 0.35    E = Modulus of elasticity for drum material, psi</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plain Bearing PV</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/formulae/components/bearing_plainpv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/formulae/components/bearing_plainpv/</guid>
      <description>Notes &amp;amp; Use Calculates design values (velocity, force, and combined) of plain bearings when the following are true:
 For radial (journal) applications  the bearing rotates around a shaft, the rotational motion is continuous (as opposed to an ocillating), the load is applied perpidicular to the axis of rotation (radial).   For thrust applications:  the load rotates upon the bearing, around a fixed center point, the thrust bearing&amp;rsquo;s bearing surface is circular or annular, the rotational motion is continuous, the load is applied parallel to the axis of rotation, the load is uniform across the surface area of the bearing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bearing Rolling Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/formulae/components/bearing_rolling_life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/formulae/components/bearing_rolling_life/</guid>
      <description>Notes &amp;amp; Use Calculates design values related to lifetime for rolling element bearings when the following is true:
 The bearing operation is not characterized as an occilating motion; the spinning object tends to make full rotations at a roughly constant speed. The RPM shall be approximated as an average RPM over the lifetime of the bearing. The radial and thrust loads have been converted to an equivalent load as per the bearing manufacturer&amp;rsquo;s reccomendations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoyo Drum Cable Payout</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/formulae/drums/drums_yoyopayout/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/formulae/drums/drums_yoyopayout/</guid>
      <description>Notes &amp;amp; Use Calculates the payout (in feet), and total number of wraps for a yoyo drum, with the following considerations&amp;hellip;
 the yoyo drum must have a single line per groove, the calculation is a simplified method that divides the area of the usuable wraps by the cable diameter. This method is not exact, but is more than adequate for the purposes of stage machines; it estimates the area of the cable pack, and divides that quantity by the cable diameter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parallel Shaft Keys</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/formulae/components/keys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/formulae/components/keys/</guid>
      <description>Notes &amp;amp; Use Calculates for the selection and design of parallel keys in shafts. Only compressive and shear stresses are taken into account. This calculator does not take into consideration:
 tolerances related to proper fits in a keyway localized stresses strength of the shaft and/or hub relative to the key material abrasion and fatigue resistance stresses caused by key rolling or cyclic impact loads  All key depths are assumed to be (0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pulley Pressures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/formulae/components/pulleys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/formulae/components/pulleys/</guid>
      <description>Notes &amp;amp; Use Calculates:
  D:d ratios for given pulley and cable sizes
  Tread pressure
 Pressure exerted on the groove by the load Wrap angle is taken into account, see image A round cable is assumed A properly-sized round groove is assumed, the nominal groove diameter is approximately: $$ D_{groove} = 1.06 \times D_{cable} $$ Note that the tread pressure as depicted in the figure below is not technically accurate, but more illustrative in nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capstan Holding Forces</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/formulae/forces/capstan_holding_force/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/formulae/forces/capstan_holding_force/</guid>
      <description>gimmick: math
Capstan Holding Forces Notes &amp;amp; Use Calculates the relationship between a hold-force and load-force of a flexible line wrapped around a cylinder, such as a capstan or drum.
This calculator will calculate for either the hold-force or load-force by way of a user-selected drop down menu.
Figure Terms H = hold, pounds force (Newtons)
w = number of wraps
Φ = angle of wrap, radians
μ = coeficient of friction</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>D:d Ratio</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/formulae/geometry/d-to-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/formulae/geometry/d-to-d/</guid>
      <description>gimmick: math
D:d Ratio Notes &amp;amp; Use Calculates:
 D:d ratios for given pulley and cable sizes Adjusted capacity of wire rope due to D:d bend  Note: that at a D:d ratio of 10 and less, permanent distortions of the rope will occur. (This is a general rule of thumb, different construction ropes will vary.)    Figure Terms Dtread= Tread diameter, inches
Dcable= Cable diameter, inches
Equations Pitch Diameter, inches: $$ D_{pitch} = D_{tread} + D_{cable}$$</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet Angle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/formulae/geometry/fleet_angle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/formulae/geometry/fleet_angle/</guid>
      <description>gimmick: math
Fleet Angle Notes &amp;amp; Use Calculates the allowable offset distance and distance from a pulley or drum with respect to an included angle.
This calculator will calculate for all three variables by way of a user-selected drop down menu.
Figure Terms d = Offset distance, units of length
D = Distance from pulley or drum, units of length
φ = included angle, degrees
Equations $$ \phi = atan , \left( \frac {d}{D} \right) $$</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleet Angle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/formulae/navigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/formulae/navigation/</guid>
      <description>Formulae List Calculator Index
Formula Index
 ANSI Roller Chain Bearings: Plain Radial PV calculator Bearings: Roller Lifetime Capstan Holding Force D:d Ratio Drums: Helical Payout Drums: Yoyo Payout Drums: Max Unbraced Length Fleet Angle Frustum Flatten HP Force/Speed Linepull Winch Motions Parallel Keys Piston Force &amp;amp; Speed Pulley Calcs Resultant Force over a Pulley Shockload Force Yoyo Winch  gimmick:theme (inverse: false)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frustum</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/formulae/geometry/frustum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/formulae/geometry/frustum/</guid>
      <description>gimmick: math
Conical Frustum Flattener Notes &amp;amp; Use This calculator calculates the flat pattern for a right-angle conical frustum.
Figure Terms r&#39; = Top radius of conical frustum, units of length
R = Bottom radius of conical frustum, units of length
h = height of conical frustum, units of length
φ = included angle of conical frustum, radians
s&#39; = Flattened small radius, units of length
S = Flattened large radius, units of length</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HP Force/Speed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/formulae/power-transmission/hp_force_speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/formulae/power-transmission/hp_force_speed/</guid>
      <description>Notes &amp;amp; Use Calculates the relationship between HP, Force, and Velocity; this is for use when determining rough order of magnitude power transmissions.
This calculator will calculate for either velocity or force at any given time by specifiying the variable to solve for.
Terms P = Motor power, horsepower
η = efficiency, percent
v = velocity of line, feet per second
F = force of line, pounds force
Equations $$ v = \frac {550P}{F} \eta $$</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/formulae/power-transmission/motions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/formulae/power-transmission/motions/</guid>
      <description>Notes &amp;amp; Use Calculates for various motion-related values:
 time max velocity acceleration deceleration distance  Motion profiles are assumed to be trapezoidal in nature, with constant accel, decel, and max speed.
The following calculation order is observed&amp;hellip;
 Changing any value (except Time) will recalculate the Time value The Accel &amp;amp; Decel values (f/s2) will remain constant unless the Accel/Decel Distance values are edited. The Top Speed value will remain constant unless the Time value is edited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Piston Force &amp; Speed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/formulae/power-transmission/piston_force_speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/formulae/power-transmission/piston_force_speed/</guid>
      <description>gimmick: math
Piston Force &amp;amp; Speed Notes &amp;amp; Use The first section calculates the push force and pull force of a pneumatic/hydraulic piston, with the folowing considerations&amp;hellip;
 The cylinder bore and rod have circular cross-sections, The rod Ø must not exceed the bore Ø The pressure on the opposing face of the piston cup (not the pressuring side) is assumed to be at standard atmospheric pressure  The second part of this calculator calculates values related to the piston speed and displacement, where:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resultant Force</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/formulae/forces/resultant_force/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/formulae/forces/resultant_force/</guid>
      <description>gimmick: math
Resultant Force Notes &amp;amp; Use Calculates the maximum force on a pulley or pin where:
 A rope or flexible member with forces acting on both ends, turns around said pulley or pin.  Figure Terms L = Load, pounds force (Newtons)
R = Resultant force, pounds force (Newtons)
φ = included angle of wrap, degrees.
Where:
 φ ≥ 0° φ &amp;lt; 180°  Equations $$ R = 2 L , cos , \left( \frac {\phi}{2} \right) $$</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shockload</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/formulae/forces/shockload/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/formulae/forces/shockload/</guid>
      <description>gimmick: math
Shockload Force Notes &amp;amp; Use Calculates the force subjected to a body during a shockload event for the following cases:
 Distance fallen, and stopping distance Distance fallen, and wire rope type and diameter Distance fallen, and rope (percentage elongation)  by Distance Terms:    Variable Description Unit     m mass pounds   lfall Falling distance in   d Stopping distance in   Fshock Force due to shockload lbf    Equation $$ F_{shock} = m , \left( \frac {l_{fall}}{d} + 1 \right) $$</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winch Linepull</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/formulae/power-transmission/winch_linepull/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/formulae/power-transmission/winch_linepull/</guid>
      <description>gimmick: math
Linepull Winch Calcs Notes &amp;amp; Usage Calculates a simple winch arragement in which there exists:
 A motor A reduction stage A drum or sprocket stage with constant diameter  This calculator will recalculate if any of the values are changed. There are three sets of calculations performed depending on the values that are changed. Each set of calculations are based on the formulas provided in the Calculation section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoyo Winch Calcs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/formulae/power-transmission/winch_yoyo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/formulae/power-transmission/winch_yoyo/</guid>
      <description>gimmick: math
Yoyo Winch Calcs Notes &amp;amp; Usage Calculates a simple winch arragement in which there exists:
 A motor A reduction stage A yoyo (or pilewind) drum.  The behavior of this system is such that at any time during the machine&amp;rsquo;s operation, the linepull velocity and force are changing depending on the diameter of the drum. E.g. as the motor drives at a constant speed, the drum pulls in cable.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
