<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Formulae _index.em.md page! on Documentation for the Scenic-Shop Calculators</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/formulae/formulae/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Formulae _index.em.md page! on Documentation for the Scenic-Shop Calculators</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/formulae/formulae/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Plain Bearing PV</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/formulae/formulae/bearing_plainpv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/formulae/formulae/bearing_plainpv/</guid>
      <description>Bearings: Plain PV Notes &amp;amp; Use Calculates design values (velocity, force, and combined) of plain bearings when the following are true:
 For radial (journal) applications  the bearing rotates around a shaft, the rotational motion is continuous (as opposed to an ocillating), the load is applied perpidicular to the axis of rotation (radial).   For thrust applications:  the load rotates upon the bearing, around a fixed center point, the thrust bearing&amp;rsquo;s bearing surface is circular or annular, the rotational motion is continuous, the load is applied parallel to the axis of rotation, the load is uniform across the surface area of the bearing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bearing Rolling Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/formulae/formulae/bearing_rolling_life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/formulae/formulae/bearing_rolling_life/</guid>
      <description>Rolling Bearing Life Notes &amp;amp; Use Calculates design values related to lifetime for rolling element bearings when the following is true:
 The bearing operation is not characterized as an occilating motion; the spinning object tends to make full rotations at a roughly constant speed. The RPM shall be approximated as an average RPM over the lifetime of the bearing. The radial and thrust loads have been converted to an equivalent load as per the bearing manufacturer&amp;rsquo;s reccomendations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
